<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<portfolioJ>

<!-- Image 1--> 
	<title> Nisshinkogyo Competition </title>
	<largeImage>portfolioJ/large/01.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>portfolioJ/thumbs/01.jpg</thumbImage>
        <description> Puppet performer’s house
Artist: The fictional artist is a puppet performer and crafter. He and his wife performed with puppets for children, for many years in a big city centre. A tragedy occurred and he lost his wife in an accident, which also left him disabled. He now uses a wheelchair and his art is more of a puppet crafting than performance. His daughter also studied performance. They came really close after the accident and now they live in a complete symbiosis of life and arts. He creates, whereas she performs, so as to keep both their arts alive. They need to perform and live together, in a space that enables it.
Concept: The concept model (image 1) represents the puppet performance. The two concrete walls are the husband and wife, the puppet creator and performer. Since the wife’s passing, the daughter becomes the second artist, the performer. So a new wall is added to create a new space for their co-existence in arts and life (image 4). This new wall which represents the daughter separates the public space from the private and also connects the performing with the puppet creation.
The house is in the centre of a city in a corner site. Since the first artist is disabled all inclusive design aspects are taken into consideration. The house is design so as to amplify the relationship between the father and the daughter, the puppet crafter and the puppet performer, their need to live and work together as one.
 </description>
	
<!-- Image 2--> 
	<title> Nisshinkogyo Competition </title>
	<largeImage>portfolioJ/large/02.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>portfolioJ/thumbs/01.jpg</thumbImage>
        <description> Inspiration and creation in a natural slope
Artists: The couple of artists are a famous fictional writer and his wife, a garden planner/artist. Their different forms of art, provide two contrasting approaches in the house design which collide into a symbiosis of arts, like the couple’s life.
Concept: The writers approach derives from Onomichi temple district which has a natural path in the forest slope, which writers use to walk for inspiration. The Garden artist’s concept is this of Japanese ‘Dandan’ rice levelled fields. Those two ideas bring together, form a house in a slope which serves both artist’s living and art purposes. 
The rice level fields are now the house rooms and gardens. Every section of the house has a ‘natural’ form in a different level with green roof to be used as gardens. The whole house is formed around the ‘Onomichi’ existing path in the slope. This path represents the writer’s path. A new path is created along the house forms, which used as a shortcut for the existing one and also connects all the gardens together. That new path represents the garden artist’s art.
The two paths create spaces in between which can be separated in private for writer or his wife and public, for both of them and potential guests. This difference in the houses space is also expressed in materiality. The private writer’s space is made of a more ‘natural’ stone masonry, whereas the garden artist’s private spaces (two interior garden rooms) are using corten (rusted) steel. Their shared spaces share materials as well, with the use of gabions (stones in steel cages).
</description>

<!-- Image 3--> 
	<title> Tohoku Competition </title>
	<largeImage>portfolioJ/large/03.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>portfolioJ/thumbs/03.jpg</thumbImage>
        <description> The Idea:
The idea initiates from Onomichi complex of small streets, alleys and paths. One can walk and enjoy quite green spaces, steep slopes, narrow paths in between big rocks, meeting path points and much more. This variety creates a unique experience for walking. Something that most habitants of a big city rarely enjoy in their everyday routine.
The Concept:
Focusing in Hiroshima city centre the idea develops in a complex path network. Five small parks in the heart of Hiroshima are considered the starting points of some complex paths, which connect each other. Those five green spaces initiate a network, which follows a complex pattern through the urban fabric, with new connections only to be the secondary objective. The basis for this idea is mainly to provide a unique experience to the Hiroshima city’s inhabitants. An experience one can get to the complex paths of Onomichi, with all the characteristics it provides.
By focusing on the Hiroshima Park, we study in detail the possible routes through the existing buildings and how the variety of ‘Onomichi’ experiences are placed into the Hiroshima’s new path. 
</description>
	
<!-- Image 4--> 
	<title> Haseko Competition </title>
	<largeImage>portfolioJ/large/04.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>portfolioJ/thumbs/04.jpg</thumbImage>
        <description> Concept:
The two axis of the project are ‘Sustainability’ and ‘Community’. The initial idea to contain those two main aspects was a modular form of apartment builds which would be flexible and expandable. The thirty apartment proposal is only an initial stage of the project, in which in time and as the community expands or creates bonds, the proposal evolves with more connections between the apartments and shared spaces. 
A one person apartment will be easily get evolved to a two person apartment or to a family apartment and so on. Also an apartment can also connect with a shared space (green roof, garden or even glass house garden) with another apartment creating bonds and shared activities thus a stronger community. The modular form of the buildings allows this evolution with a variety of choice designs.
The ‘community’ aspect is enforced through the modularity of the design, to a number of possibilities in that community’s expansion/evolution.
Sustainability is expressed through both the choice of materials and the everyday community activities. Materiality such as local timber and recycled steel is used for the main units. Recycled aggregate paving, natural gravels and stones selected from local sources. Wild green roofs, living walls and use of native planting are supporting the wildlife in the region, increasing the biodiversity. Rain water harvesting, permeable and geothermal paving allow water to be stored in a sub base and generate sufficient energy to allow transference of heat in and out of a building. Heat pumps using the earth's ground temperature and extract energy to cool the buildings and support the heat in the winter.
Green spaces such as green roofs and green glass houses, adding to the community’s sustainability in the form of vegetable and fruit production for every residence. Possibly leading to trading interactions, sharing and moreover expansion to more shared spaces, thus more building connection/evolution. 
</description>

<!-- Image 5--> 
	<title> Itsumikai Competition </title>
	<largeImage>portfolioJ/large/05.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>portfolioJ/thumbs/05.jpg</thumbImage>
        <description> Concept:
The design initiates from the pure form of the cube and by applying two basic ideas. Firstly, the heart of the cube is the heart of the family. The place where the grandparents, the parents and the children will spend most of the time together. This place has to be visible to the neighbours so as  to work as an inspiration for them. By creating this special place we also create a ‘void’ mass that will subtract from the main house cube mass. This will allow that space to become ’semi-private’ with visual access but not physical.
The next idea has to do with the shape of the voids and how they allow light and vision to the ‘heart’ of the house. By creating angles to the openings vision from outside its easier thus the idea of the ‘united family’ is greatly expanding outside the house. 
Finally the whole house is one family that is composed by two different elements, the family with the children and the grandparents. Those two elements are separated inside the house with the ;heart’ of the house to be the meeting point. Also the materiality is different with the grandparents to have a more timber bases construction, in comparison to the plain white one of the parents and children.
</description>

<!-- Image 6--> 
	<title> +Design - Earthquake Dissaster Recovery Competition </title>
	<largeImage>portfolioJ/large/06.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>portfolioJ/thumbs/06.jpg</thumbImage>
        <description> The catastrophic earthquake left a big part of the city of Sendai in a disastrous state. Massive amounts of rubble and debris are now lying where a lively part of the city used to be. One of the bigger challenges now is the removal of all that massive pile of rubble. 
The percentages of the remaining debris that now cover many square kilometres over the site are at least 50% recyclable or re-usable materials and another 50% of waste and unusable elements. Our proposal has to do with the management of that massive problem in the area, along with a memorial suggestion, because it is always good to forget a disaster but also wise to get reminded of such unfortunate possibilities.
The rubble can be lightly processed for a minor separation. The unusable can be pilled in a certain location of the city forming an artificial hill. The artificial hill can be covered in soil, which is in excess in the area, creating a potential green hill or a park for the people to visit. The idea has to do with offering something useable to the future welfare and solving a massive problem of the existing debris in the same time. 
The memorial comes as a scar to the artificial hill, in the form of a chasm that separates the hill, but creates a path inside it. The path reveals the nature of the hill and the existing of the rubbles. A reminder that a great tsunami passed through the site and spread a massive disaster. The same remains of that town are now pilled in that beautiful hill. 
The path can only come as a contrast to the beautiful, green, artificial hill, with walls made of the existing rubble, dark, with foul smell and a sense of pressure between the opposite walls. Creating uncomfortable feelings with a straight view to the sea, which is where the disaster came from. In the end of the path the memorial begins. A series of constructed paths inside the walls which contain information about the earthquake, the tsunami and everything that has to do with that disaster. A way out that takes you back from the uncomfortable experience in a more civilised, safe and informative way, leading to the present green hill park.
The construction of the hill in the area of the chasm and the memorial, takes a modular form using large gabions. The extracted steel from the rubbles is recycled and formed into specific dimensioned cages that contain the unusable rubble. Then like oversized ‘bricks’ form the chasm creating two opposing retaining walls. The excess of the rubble are placed around those walls creating/forming the core of the hill.
</description>

<!-- Image 7--> 
	<title> Concrete + Timber Competition </title>
	<largeImage>portfolioJ/large/07.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>portfolioJ/thumbs/07.jpg</thumbImage>
        <description> The Onimichi House:
Studying Onomichi, a place of interest emerged at one of the South facing slopes of the temple district hill. The dense building at the steep slope was full of patches of green and moreover full of stairs and paths. A full scale 3 or 4 people family house is nearly impossible to fit in the existing urban fabric of the place. But a tall narrow building have a variety of possible spots that can be placed without interfering with the existing network of buildings and paths
The house design initiates by the "bridge" idea and it is based in a frame design that contains the living environment. The bridge is a result of the small patches of land available for building, in regards with the number of paths existing. The house form, allows the building of a bigger house, than a simple towering structure would allow. Also allows the passage under the bridge section, thus leaving the existing paths untouched.
The use of Concrete is to create a three storey tall frame that contains the three public spaces of the house. The First floor is the Kitchen with the heart in the middle. The fire of the hearth is under a chimney which also drives the heat through and to the upper floor in which the living room is. The higher floor is the study and guest floor. The other side of the "bridge" anchoring is also made of concrete and at the base contains the mechanical services like heating, water tank, e.t.c. 
The "bridge" structure of the house contains the private section, the bathroom, toilet and the bedrooms. The whole structure is made of wood with the use of laminated small timber beams to form more durable, large span, timber beams and columns. 
</description>
		
<!-- Image 8--> 
	<title> Concrete + Timber Competition </title>
	<largeImage>portfolioJ/large/08.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>portfolioJ/thumbs/07.jpg</thumbImage>
        <description> The Onimichi House:
Studying Onomichi, a place of interest emerged at one of the South facing slopes of the temple district hill. The dense building at the steep slope was full of patches of green and moreover full of stairs and paths. A full scale 3 or 4 people family house is nearly impossible to fit in the existing urban fabric of the place. But a tall narrow building have a variety of possible spots that can be placed without interfering with the existing network of buildings and paths
The house design initiates by the "bridge" idea and it is based in a frame design that contains the living environment. The bridge is a result of the small patches of land available for building, in regards with the number of paths existing. The house form, allows the building of a bigger house, than a simple towering structure would allow. Also allows the passage under the bridge section, thus leaving the existing paths untouched.
The use of Concrete is to create a three storey tall frame that contains the three public spaces of the house. The First floor is the Kitchen with the heart in the middle. The fire of the hearth is under a chimney which also drives the heat through and to the upper floor in which the living room is. The higher floor is the study and guest floor. The other side of the "bridge" anchoring is also made of concrete and at the base contains the mechanical services like heating, water tank, e.t.c. 
The "bridge" structure of the house contains the private section, the bathroom, toilet and the bedrooms. The whole structure is made of wood with the use of laminated small timber beams to form more durable, large span, timber beams and columns. 
</description>

</portfolioJ>


