<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<portfolioA>

<!-- Image 1--> 
	<title>
A hard working person with great organisational skills when it comes to time management, with the ability to combine a variety of designing strategies for a more comprehended illustration of ideas or projects. Possessing a great ability in learning new programs or design methods, thus being adjustable in every practices ways of working. Possessing an engineer foundation and a well developed ability in physical modelling, mixed media illustration and computer drawing and illustration techniques. In addition a great eye for detail and quality in design as well as the willingness to offer and receive as much as possible.
 
        </title>
	<largeImage>about/01.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>about/1.jpg</thumbImage>
	
<!-- Image 2--> 
	<title> 2011-Current Diploma in Architecture at Kinki University Japan
2010-2011 BA(hons) in Architecture at the Edinburgh College of Art
2007-2010 BA in Architecture at the Edinburgh College of Art, Edinburgh (1st year in the University of Greenwich London)
2007 Foundation Course in Architecture in DEI (Grade 70% distinction), Thessaloniki, Greece
2001-2006 Civil Infrastructure Engineering in the Technological Educational Institute of Thessaloniki, Greece (Grade 7.12/10)
1999 Secondary School Diploma (Mathematics, Physics, Engineering, Materials science, Chemistry) (Grade 18.6/20)
Polytechnic Secondary School of Myrina, Limnos, Greece
 
        </title>
	<largeImage>about/02.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>about/2.jpg</thumbImage>

<!-- Image 3--> 
	<title> 
Hand drawing, Physical modelling, Sketching and Mixed media illustration
Computer Aided Design: 
AutoCAD 2004-2011 versions, 
AutoCAD 3D, 3ds max 9 to 11, 
Photoshop, InDesign, Flash CS 
and basic knowledge in Solidworks, Sketchup, Rinoceros.

        </title>
	<largeImage>about/03.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>about/3.jpg</thumbImage>
	
<!-- Image 4--> 
	<title> 
The A+DS and RIAS Scottish student Awards for Architecture 2010  
ARCHITECTURE + DESIGN SCOTLAND Urban Design Award: Highly Commended  
ARCHITECTURE + DESIGN SCOTLAND Award for the best 3rd year student:  Highly Commended  
THE RIAS DRAWING AWARD Commended  
RIBA The President's Medals Student Awards Nomination and Participation
        </title>
	<largeImage>about/04.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>about/4.jpg</thumbImage>

<!-- Image 5--> 
	<title> 
tsormang@gmail.com
         </title>
	<largeImage>about/05.jpg</largeImage>
	<thumbImage>about/5.jpg</thumbImage>



			
</portfolioA>


